Welcome! In the last lecture, we successfully led our character to use the custom movement
欢迎！欢迎 在上一讲中，我们成功地引导我们的角色使用我们创建的自定义运动
component that we created. And in this lecture, we'll look at how we can use this component
组件。在本讲中，我们将看看如何使用这个组件
to enable climbing. So you already know that this is the climbing process that we'll create.
来实现爬行。所以你已经知道，这是我们要创建的攀爬过程。
And the first issue that we need to solve is, we'll need to check whether or not we
我们需要解决的第一个问题是，我们需要检查我们是否
can actually start climbing. What do I mean by that? In the scenario one, when we press
能否真正开始爬升。我这样说是什么意思呢？在方案一中，当我们按下
the climb action key, we should definitely start climbing. But in scenario two and three,
攀爬动作键，我们肯定会开始攀爬。但是在情景二和情景三中、
we shouldn't be able to do so. So how to rule out these two scenarios is the key in
我们不应该这样做。因此，如何排除这两种情况是这里的关键所在
here. To do that, we need to get hold of the climbable surface info for our character.
这里的关键。要做到这一点，我们需要掌握我们角色的可攀爬表面信息。
More specifically, we need to perform some ray traces. And the next question would be
更确切地说，我们需要进行一些射线追踪。而下一个问题将是
what type of trace that we should use in here. Take the first scenario for example. The easiest
我们在这里应该使用什么类型的跟踪。以第一种情况为例。最简单的
answer might be doing a line trace. If we were only ever to be able to climb a single
最简单的答案可能是做一个线迹。如果我们只想爬上一个单一的
surface, a simple line trace would actually work. But if we are dealing with multiple
面，那么简单的直线追踪就可以了。但如果我们面对的是多个
surfaces that are overlapping with each other, a line trace won't provide us with enough
互相重叠的表面，直线追踪就不能为我们提供足够的
information for us to do the calculation. So instead, I like to use a capsule trace.
信息来进行计算。所以，我喜欢用一个胶囊追踪。
And this could help us to handle the situation where there are multiple overlapping surfaces
这可以帮助我们处理有多个重叠面的情况
in front of us. And for the second scenario, a simple line trace would do the job. So let's
在我们面前的情况。而对于第二种情况，一个简单的线迹就可以完成工作。所以让我们
take care of the first scenario. Go back to my project. I'm going to first close my project
处理第一种情况。回到我的项目中去。我将首先关闭我的项目
and go back to Visual Studio. Inside of my custom moving component class, I'm going to
然后回到Visual Studio。在我的自定义移动组件类中，我将会
create a code region just for better readability. So I'm going to type in pound region, press
创建一个代码区域，以提高可读性。所以我将输入磅数区域，按下
tab on my keyboard. And for the region name, I'm going to call it climb traces. And I'm
键盘上的TAB键。对于区域的名称，我将把它叫做 "攀登痕迹"。然后我将
going to mark this section private. And next I'm going to create a function. So this function
将会把这部分标记为私有。接下来我将创建一个函数。所以这个函数
is going to return a t array of f hit result. So I'm going to type in t array f hit result.
将会返回一个t数组的f命中结果。所以我将输入t数组f命中结果。
And I'm going to call this function to capsule trace multi by object. And it's going to have
然后我将调用这个函数，以便通过对象来捕获追踪多。它将会有
a few input parameters. So the first one is going to be a const f vector reference. I'm
几个输入参数。第一个参数是一个const f矢量参考。我将
going to call it start. The second one is going to be another const reference. I'm going
我将把它称为start。第二个将是另一个常量引用。我将
to call it end. And the third input parameter is going to be bool. I'm going to call it
称之为end。第三个输入参数将是bool。我将把它叫做
b show debug shape. And I'm going to give it a default value of false. And I'm going
b显示调试形状。我将给它一个默认值false。然后我将
to use Visual Studio to create a function definition. So I'm going to paste the function in my cpp
使用Visual Studio来创建一个函数定义。所以我将把这个函数粘贴到我的cpp
file. Then I'm also going to paste the region to my cpp file. And the trace function that
文件中。然后我也要把这个区域粘贴到我的cpp文件中。而我喜欢使用的跟踪函数
I like to use is from Kizma system library. So we'll need to include its header file.
我喜欢用的是Kizma系统库。所以我们需要包括它的头文件。
And the fastest way to find out the full file name for us to include be searching for it.
最快的方法是通过搜索来找出我们要包含的完整文件名。
So I'm going to go to the search bar here and I'm going to type in Kizma system library.
所以我要去搜索栏，输入Kizma系统库。
And you can see this is the header file that we need. A lot of handy functions that we
你可以看到这就是我们需要的头文件。很多方便的函数，我们
use inside the footprint like print string or delete are all from this library. So I'm
像打印字符串或删除都是来自这个库。所以我
going to go to its cpp file, double click to open it. And I'm going to copy the first
所以我要去找它的cpp文件，双击打开它。然后我将复制第一
line. This is the correct include we need. And I'm going to paste it to my custom movement
行。这就是我们需要的正确的包含。我将把它粘贴到我的自定义运动的
component cpp. And I'm going to start to implement this function. So I'm going to copy this Kizma
组件的cpp文件。我将开始实现这个功能。所以我将复制这个Kizma
system library and I'm going to paste it in here. Add u in front of it. Then double column
系统库，并将其粘贴到这里。在它前面加上u。然后双列
we can access all the static functions inside. And the function that we need to use is called
我们可以访问里面所有的静态函数。而我们需要使用的函数叫做
capsule trace multi for objects. So by using this function, we can get multiple hit results
capsule trace multi for objects。所以通过使用这个函数，我们可以得到多个命中结果
if there are multiple surfaces in front of us. And as you can see, there are quite a
如果在我们面前有多个表面。正如你所看到的，有相当多的
lot of input parameters that we need to fill in. So the first one, it'll be a word context
我们需要填入很多输入参数。所以，第一个参数，是一个词的上下文
object. I'm going to fill in this. And the second one, this will be the start of the
对象。我将填入这个。第二个，这将是追踪的开始。
trace. I'm going to fill in the start, our input parameter. And the end will be our end.
追踪的开始。我将填入开始，即我们的输入参数。末端将是我们的终点。
And in here we need to define the caps of radius and half height. And there's something that
在这里我们需要定义半径和半高的上限。还有一些东西
I want to control through variables exposed to blueprint. So I'm going to go back to my
我想通过暴露在蓝图中的变量来控制。所以我将回到我的
header file and under this region, I'm going to create a new one. So for this region, I'm
头文件，在这个区域下，我将创建一个新的区域。因此，对于这个区域，我将
going to call it climbed variables. And I'm going to type in u property, edit defaults
我将把它称为 "攀登变量"。我将输入u属性，编辑默认值
only and blueprint re only. And the category, all the variables inside the character movement
和蓝图re only。在这个类别中，所有在角色运动中的变量
component follow a very specific naming convention. I'm going to follow that in here. So you'll
组件的所有变量都遵循一个非常具体的命名规则。我将在这里遵循这个惯例。所以你会
be character movement followed by a colon. And I'm going to type in climbing. And since
角色运动，后面加一个冒号。我将输入 "攀登"。由于
this is a private variable, we just market blueprint re only, we don't need to give it
由于这是一个私有变量，我们只需要在市场上销售蓝图，我们不需要给它
the meta specifier. And we can copy that from our character class. So I'm going to go to
元指定器。我们可以从我们的角色类中复制它。所以我将进入
the header file of our character class and I'm going to copy this and paste it back to
角色类的头文件，然后复制这个并把它粘贴到
this header file. And for the variable type, it's going to be a float. I'm going to call
这个头文件。对于变量类型，它将是一个float。我将把它称为
it climbed capsule trace radius. And I'm going to give it a default value of 50.f. Then I'm
它被称为 "攀登的胶囊轨迹半径"。我将给它一个默认值50.f。
going to copy this u property. And for the second one, it's going to be another float.
复制这个u属性。对于第二个属性，它将是另一个浮点数。
And I'm going to call it climbed capsule trace half height and give it a default value of
我将把它称为攀登的胶囊跟踪的一半高度，并给它一个默认值为
72.f. All right, I'm going to fill in these two variables inside of this function. So
72.f。好的，我要把这两个变量填入这个函数中。所以
this will be the radius. This will be the half height. All right. And the next parameter
这将是半径。这将是一半的高度。好的。而下一个参数
that we need to fill in. So it needs to be a t array of type E object type query. For
我们需要填入的。所以它需要是一个E型对象类型查询的t数组。对于
our climb trace here, I'm only interested in the object of type word static. Instead
我们在这里的攀登跟踪，我只对静态字类型的对象感兴趣。而不是
of creating a local variable and add element to it, every time we run the function, I like
而不是创建一个局部变量并向其添加元素，每次我们运行函数时，我喜欢
to create another member variable for this type. And as you can see, it's a pretty long
为这个类型创建另一个成员变量。正如你所看到的，这是个相当长的
type. So the fastest way for us to get to that will be go to the function body of this capsule
类型。所以我们最快的方法是进入这个胶囊的函数体
trace multi. So press F12. Then you can go to the function body in here. Then I'm going
追踪多。所以按F12。然后你可以进入这里的函数体。然后我将
to copy this. Then go back to my header file. I'm going to paste it at the top and I'm going
复制这个。然后回到我的头文件中去。我将把它粘贴在顶部，然后我将
to call this variable climbable surface trace types. And it needs to have the same u property
将这个变量称为可攀登表面追踪类型。它需要有相同的u属性
as below. So copy this one and paste it in here. Then back to my cpp file. I'm going
和下面一样。所以复制这个并粘贴到这里。然后回到我的cpp文件。我将
to fill in this variable. All right. The next one that we need to fill in is this b trace
填入这个变量。好的。下一个我们需要填写的是这个b跟踪
complex. I'm going to fill in false. And next one will be an array of a actor. So this is
复杂。我将填写false。而下一个将是一个数组的a actor。所以这就是
the actors to ignore. I'm going to fill in an empty array. So it will be t array a actor
要忽略的演员。我将填入一个空数组。所以它将是一个数组a actor
followed by a parenthesis and the next parameter. So this is an enum. It's called e draw debug
后面有一个括号和下一个参数。所以这是一个枚举。它被称为e draw debug
trace and we have an input parameter for that. So I'm going to copy the name of this and
追踪，我们有一个输入参数用于此。所以我将复制这个名字并
I'm going to paste it in here and I'm going to use a ternary operator in here. So when
我要把它粘贴到这里，并在这里使用一个三元运算符。所以当
this is true, I'm going to fill in e draw debug trace double colon for one frame. And
为真时，我将填入一帧的e draw debug trace的双冒号。而
when this is false, I'm going to fill in none. So later we can easily define where dot none
当它为假时，我将填入无。所以以后我们可以很容易地定义在哪里点无
we want to see the debug shapes in here. And the next one that we need to fill in is an
我们想在这里看到调试形状。下一个我们需要填写的是一个
out parameter. So this is the hit results that we are after. For that, I'm going to
out参数。所以这是我们所要的命中结果。为了这个，我将
create a local variable for it. So the type is going to be t array of hit result. I'm
为它创建一个局部变量。所以类型将是命中结果的t数组。我将
going to call it out capsule trace hit results and fill in this array.
将调用它的胶囊跟踪命中结果并填入这个数组。
And the last parameter that we need to fill in is this be ignore self. I'm going to fill
我们需要填入的最后一个参数是：忽略自我。我将填写
in false. All right, that's all the function parameters that we need to fill in and don't
false。好了，这就是我们需要填入的所有函数参数，别忘了在后面加上分号。
forget to put semi colon after it. And at the end of this function, I'm going to return
别忘了在它后面加上分号。在这个函数的最后，我将返回
this out capsule trace hit results. And that's pretty much it. I'm going to press control
这个胶囊的跟踪结果。这就差不多了。我将按控制键
plus B to compile. All right, I have a successful compile. Now we just reduce the amount of input
加B来编译。好的，我有一个成功的编译。现在我们只要把输入参数的数量
parameters to three. And later when we need to perform capsule trace multiple times, you'll
参数减少到三个。以后当我们需要多次执行胶囊跟踪时，你就会
be much easier for us to do so. Later when you implement this by yourself, same as I did,
我们就能更容易地做到了。以后当你自己实现这个的时候，和我一样、
you can search for the name of this file that we need to include and find out the full name
你可以搜索我们需要包含的这个文件的名称，并找出其CPP文件中的全名
inside of its CPP file. As for the function we use, as you can see, there are plenty of
在它的CPP文件中。至于我们使用的函数，正如你所看到的，有很多的
input parameters that we need to fill in. Feel free to refer back to the video if you need
输入参数，我们需要填入这些参数。如果你需要帮助，请随时回看视频。
help. All right, it's time for you to do the same and I'll see you in the next lecture.
帮助。好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了，我们在下一个讲座中见。
[Music]
[音乐]